So the answer is: this loop will essentially run forever.
答案是 该循环会永远运行下去
It won't run till the end of the universe,
它不会运行到宇宙的终结
because we'll probably have something else happen to our computer before that.
因为在那之前我们的电脑可能已经出问题了
But there's no stopping condition for the "while" loop.
但是确实不存在让这一 while 循环停止的条件
The "while" test will never become False.
该 while 判断永远不会为假
We start with "i" equals 1.
在开始时 i 等于1
We keep increasing by 2, so the values that I will have
不断地让 i 加2
will be 1, 3, 5, 7, 9, 11, and so forth.
i 的值将会是 1, 3, 5, 7, 9, 11……
The loop test checks if "i" is equal to 10.
该循环判断检查 i 是否等于10
If "i" is not equal to 10, we keep going.
如果 i 不等于10 我们就继续
So if "i" is not equal to 10, we're going to keep going through the loop.
所以如果 i 不等于10 我们就不断执行这个循环
"i" will never become 10--we skip 10.
i 永远不会等于10——我们跳过了10
The loop test is never True--that means the "while" loop just keeps going
该循环判断永远不会为真——这意味着它会一直继续下去
forever and ever, never finishing.
永远不会结束
I'll show you what happens when we run that.
下面我们来运行这些代码 看看会发生什么
And I'm going to show this running in the Python shell
我将在 Python 命令行解释器里运行这些代码
instead of running through the Web browser ID that you've been using so far in the class.
而不是在你们之前课上使用的浏览器里
And the reason for that is we can see more output.
因为这样我们能看到更多输出
We can run longer things that--the way you run the programs for class,
我们可以运行更长的代码——你们在课上运行的程序
there's a limit to how long they can run and how big the output can be.
其运行长度和输出量都是有限制的
With the shell, there's no limit like that,
而命令行解释器则没有这样的限制
so I can show you a longer execution.
所以我们能执行更长的代码
There are instructions on the Web site,
如果你们自己想在 Python 命令行解释器里运行程序
if you want to run programs yourself in the Python shell.
网站上有相关说明
There are lots of different ways to do that, and instructions for how to do that
你们可以用很多不同的方式
on different platforms.
网站上也有如何在不同平台上运行的相关说明
It is not necessary to continue with the class,
这对于本课程并不是必要的
but it will make it easier to see what's going on here.
但是你们了解一下总是有好处的
So here's the code.
下面是代码
I'm going to enter the code that we had,
我将输入我们已有的代码
so we have "i" is assigned 1,
所以 i 赋值为1
and then the loop, "while i is not equal to 10".
然后是循环 当 i 不等于10
We're going to increase "i" by 2,
我们将让 i 加上2
and then we're going to print "i".
然后我们将打印 i
So now when I type return one more time,
现在 当我再次返回
this "while" loop will start running,
这一 while 循环就会开始运行
and we'll see it print out the numbers
我们就会看到这些数字被打印出来
and it will keep going as long as we let it keep going.
该程序会一直运行下去
So here we go.
现在让我们来看一看
We see 3, 5, 7, notes keeping going, really fast.
我们看到 3 5 7 还在继续 速度很快
So at the top, you can see the first 5 numbers:
在最上面 你能看到最前面的5个数字
it started at 3, 5, 7, 9, 11.
也就是3, 5, 7, 9, 11
Since it skipped 10, the loop didn't stop.
程序跳过了10 所以该循环不会停止
This condition was never False.
判断条件永远不会为假
And it keeps going--and it will keep going for as long as we let it print
只要我们让它继续打印 程序就会继续运行
or until our computer runs out of memory or power.
除非电脑内存不够或是没电了
So a loop that never stops like this
像这样永不停止的循环
is what we call an infinite loop.
我们就称之为无限循环
That means it keeps going forever, and if you run
程序可以永远运行下去
programs on computers, you've probably encountered them a lot--
在计算机上运行程序时 你很可能遇到过很多这种情况
not just in the program that you just wrote,
不仅仅是在你们刚才写的那个程序里
that we just used for this quiz,
在我们小练习用的程序里
but oftentimes, when your software hangs
一般来说 当软件宕机
and gets stuck doing something--that's what's going on,
停止响应
that there's some mistake that a programmer made.
那就是程序员犯了些错误
We call that a bug--there's a bug in the program,
我们称其为程序的 bug
and it's stuck in an infinite loop; it's never going to make any progress.
程序卡在一个无限循环里 永远不会往下运行
It's got stuck in something where the test condition will never be True
判断条件永远不会为真 (此处是口误 应为判断条件永远不会为假)
and it's going to keep going forever.
循环会永远地继续下去